We're going to spend a little bit more time with GPT just to try out a few more interesting things.
GPT와 시간을 더 보내면서 몇 가지 흥미로운 걸 시도할 거예요
I want to start with a question that used to be asked of an earlier version of GPT.
초기 버전의 GPT에서 자주 받던 질문으로 시작할게요
I think it was GPT two to show its limitations, and we'll see whether it still has a problem with it.
GPT 2가 한계를 보여준 것 같아요 여전히 문제가 있는지 두고 봐야죠
The famous question was how many rainbows?
다들 무지개가 몇 개냐고 물었죠
Sounding interesting?
흥미롭죠?
How many rainbows does it take to leap from Hawaii to 17?
하와이에서 17개까지 뛰려면 무지개가 몇 개 필요할까요?
An interesting question.
흥미로운 질문이네요
And GPT two, I think it was, responded very firmly that it takes three rainbows to leap from Hawaii
GPT 2의 반응은 아주 단호했어요 하와이에서 17로 가려면 무지개가 세
to 17, clearly missing the nuance of the question.
개여야 한다는데 질문의 뉘앙스를 놓치고 있죠
Uh, but GPT four has no such problem.
GPT 4에는 그런 문제가 없어요
You'll see.
두고 봐요
It gives back a witty and fun response, and it even includes a rainbow emoji in its response.
재치 있고 재밌는 리액션을 보내 주는데 무지개 이모티콘도 같이 보내 줘요
It's astonishing.
정말 놀라워요
So there you have it, a very easy to deal with this kind of trickery and in fact, because GPT four
이런 속임수를 다루기가 아주 쉬워요 GPT 4O는 O는 옴니의
O, the O stands for Omni, representing that it is multimodal.
약자인데 멀티모달을 나타내죠
We can of course say please generate an image of this.
물론 이미지 생성을 요청할 수도 있죠
And it's you know, I know everyone has seen this sort of thing before, but it's funny to think that
이런 건 다들 본 적 있겠지만 생각해 보면 재미있어요 몇
just a few years ago, people were debating whether it would ever be possible to have an LLM that would
년 전만 해도 상상력과 창의력을 발휘할 수 있는 LLM이 가능할지
be able to show some kind of imagination or creativity, and now it's almost a foregone conclusion that
논의가 많았거든요 그런데 이제는 이런 결론이 나올 것 같아요
this, this kind of thing can be generated, this astonishing picture of Hawaii, the number 17 and
하와이의 놀라운 사진을 만들 수 있다고요 무지개 17개가 저기로 가고
leaps of rainbows getting there.
있어요
I mean, it's honestly it's just amazing.
솔직히 정말 놀라워요
Absolutely amazing.
정말 놀라워요
Uh, so and it even explains itself and it's, uh.
그 자체로도 설명이 돼요
Yeah, it's so very effective at this kind of creative challenge.
이런 창의적인 과제에 아주 효과적이에요
All right, on a different note, let's try out GPT four with canvas.
그럼 이쯤에서 GPT 4를 캔버스로 시험해 보죠
Another of the newer features that we have from GPT.
GPT의 또 다른 새로운 기능인데요
Um, and this allows you to work very collaboratively with, uh, with OpenAI.
오픈AI와 협업할 수 있는 좋은 기회죠
Um, and let's let's look back to the Python question that I had asked you a while ago.
파이썬 으로 돌아가서, 제가 전에 질문했던 것인데요
Let's say, um, please use canvas to work with me with this code.
캔버스를 이용해 이 코드를 작업한다고 해보죠
Uh.
네
Let's see.
어디 보죠
Yield.
항복해요
From now, I'll do something that's maybe not.
지금부터는 안 될 일을 할 거예요
I'll change it a little bit.
비트를 좀 바꿀게요
Yield from, uh, book get author for book in books, uh, using a list comprehension.
책에서 작가로 책 인 북을 get get 명령에서 목록해독을 사용하세요
And I'm not telling it what books are or what this means.
책이 뭔지, 이게 무슨 의미인지 설명하진 않겠어요
I'm just giving it this line of code and seeing what it makes of it.
코드 한 줄을 주고 어떻게 되는지 볼게요
So let's see what happens now.
이제 어떻게 되는지 보죠
So first of all, it opens up this canvas that you'll see on the right hand side, which gives us an
먼저 오른쪽에 보이는 캔버스가 열립니다 이 코드에 반복할
ability to iterate with it on this code.
수 있는 기능을 주죠
Uh, okay.
네
And there it has it.
저기 있네요
Um, uh, it's showing the code.
코드가 뜨는데요
Please, uh, extend this to show an example of this being used And what we'll see now is you'll see
이걸 확장해 이게 사용된 예제를 보여주세요 이제 일종의 커서가 이동하는 걸 보실 수 있습니다
a sort of cursor going through, and it's going to rewrite and embellish, enrich what we had there.
우리가 갖고 있던 걸 다시 쓰고 꾸미고 풍성하게 하죠
And so now that piece of code has been turned into a generator.
그 코드 조각이 이제 발전기로 바뀌었어요
It's got some data that gives an example.
예제를 제공하는 데이터가 있어요
And it's understood that there are books with a title and an author, and it's got like a little test
책의 제목과 저자가 정해져 있다고 알고 있는데 시험 삼아 보여드린
example of it.
거예요
So effective the way you saw it coming through and rewriting.
대본을 다시 쓰는 게 아주 효과적이었어요
So now let's say please modify this code so that the generator excludes books with a missing or empty
이제 코드를 수정하라고 하죠 저자가 없거나 빈 책은 생성기에서 제외되도록요
And you can imagine this might be like a business requirement that comes through.
비즈니스 요구 사항 같은 걸 상상해 보세요
Uh, and what you'll see there is something that looks really similar to the code I had there.
저기 보이는 건 제가 갖고 있던 코드와 아주 유사해 보이죠
It went through it, gave some more examples with an empty and a missing book, and then it rewrote
빈 책과 빠진 책이 있는 예시를 더 보여주더니 이 줄을 다시
this line.
썼어요
It's so, so good the way that it that it's able to sort of interactively add to what we've done before.
정말 좋은 방법이에요 우리가 전에 했던 것에 상호작용적으로 추가할 수 있으니까요
And so now let's say please update this so that it only yields unique authors.
이걸 업데이트해 달라고 하죠 독특한 작가들만 나오게요
I'm being sort of loose with my language.
제가 말을 좀 막 했어요
I'm not saying even what what I want it to to to update.
업데이트 하고 싶은 것도 말 안 했어요
And now through it goes and it's done the job it's gone through.
이제 다 됐어요 제 역할을 다했죠
It's added in another example with the same author, and it's updated this code so that it uses a set
다른 예제에 같은 작성자로 추가됐어요 이 코드를 업데이트해서 세트를
to keep track of what it's seen and only yield unique cases.
이용해 뭐가 나왔는지 추적하고 고유한 케이스만 제공하죠
Now, this is in fact, I think, a better solution than the one liner that I had.
사실 이게 제가 생각했던 것보다 더 나은 해결책 같아요
But it is lengthier.
하지만 더 길어요
But there are various reasons why it's probably better to do it that way, but let's still see if I
하지만 그렇게 하는 게 나은 이유는 여러 가지가 있겠지만 get이
can't get it.
가능한지 보죠
To rewrite this in a simpler way, let's just say is it possible to rewrite the Yield authors generator?
이걸 더 간단하게 다시 쓰려면 생산자 생성기를 다시 쓸 수 있을까요?
Let's just say to simplify.
간단히 말하자면요
To simplify the let's let it have a shot at that.
단순화하기 위해 시도해 보도록 하죠
Through it goes.
통과해요
It's not changing that.
그건 변하지 않아요
And there we go.
다 됐어요
And it has indeed done exactly basically, again, slightly better than the code that I had left you
다시 말씀드리지만 이전 슬라이드에서 보여드린 코드보다 약간 더
with on a previous slide.
나은데요
It uses the curly braces to represent the set.
중괄호를 이용해서 집합을 나타내고요
Uh, it could have just said yield from that line, but it's chosen to do it this way, and it looks
그냥 저 선에서 양보하라고 할 수도 있었지만 이렇게 하기로 선택됐어요 아주
very effective to me.
효과적으로 보이네요
So I am staggered by the whole experience of working with GPT in this way, and the way that you're
저는 GPT로 작업하는 전체적인 경험에 충격을 받았습니다 상호작용을 할 수 있고
able to be so interactive, the way it will do things like build example data and it will update things
빌드 예시 데이터도 하고 업데이트도 하고 어떻게 되는지 보여
and show you what happens.
주니까요
So yeah, extremely powerful and something which I really encourage you to use as we're going through
아주 강력한 기능이죠 이 코스를 진행하면서 막히는 게 있을 때 꼭 사용하시길
this course and you get things that you're stuck with, the trick if it doesn't bring up the canvas,
권장합니다 비결은 캔버스를 불러오지 않을 경우
is to use the words use canvas, and then it will come up and use this as a tool at your disposal to
get canvas 사용이라고 하면 여러분이 원하는 도구로 이걸 사용해 설명하고
help explain and work through problems and ideas.
문제와 아이디어를 해결하죠